racing-reference.info 2018-11-04

# Privacy Policy - Racing-Reference.info

**RACING-REFERENCE.INFO PRIVACY POLICY**

Racing-reference.info knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy very seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. By visiting our website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy covers Racing-reference.info's treatment of personal information that Racing-reference.info gathers when you are on the Racing-reference.info website and when you use Racing-reference.info services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Racing-reference.info does not own or control, or to individuals that Racing-reference.info does not employ or manage. 

**_Information Collected by Racing-reference.info_**

We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website. This information allows us to provide you with a customized and efficient experience. We do not process this information in a way that is incompatible with this objective. We collect the following types of information from our Racing-reference.info users: 

1\. Information You Provide to Us: We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features. 

2\. Automatic Information: 

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. Racing-reference.info and its authorized agents automatically receive and record certain "traffic data" on their server logs from your browser including your IP address, Racing-reference.info cookie information, and the page you requested. Racing-reference.info uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the website. Racing-reference.info may collect and, on any page, display the total counts that page has been viewed. 

Racing-reference.info also stores the following information: the content of all comments, the username of all commenters, and the username, password and email address of all approved bloggers. 

Many companies offer programs that help you to visit websites anonymously. While Racing-reference.info will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these programs are available. 

3\. E-mail Communications: Racing-reference.info is very concerned about your privacy and we will never provide your email address to a third party without your explicit permission, as detailed in the "Sharing Your Information" section below. Racing-reference.info may send out e-mails with Racing-reference.info-related news, products, offers, surveys or promotions. 

**_Cookies_**

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. Racing-reference.info cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or e-mail address is. 

The "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We recommend that you leave the cookies activated because cookies allow you to use some of Racing-reference.info's coolest features. 

**_Your Ad Choices_**

Advertising enables us to provide the rich content, and to provide much of this content free of cost to our users. Thus, we strive to provide you with ads that are relevant to you and for products you may want. However, we also offer you choices with regard to interest-based ads. 

To learn more about interest-based ads and the choices available to you, please visit our Ad Choices page, which has general information about certain companies that place these ads. Additionally, we sometimes utilize Adobe technology to customize advertising you may see on our site or other sites. You can opt out of the receipt of targeted advertising utilizing Adobe technology by clicking [here](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html). 

You may also find more information about entities involved in online advertising and additional choices you may make through the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") at the [NAI site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (the "DAA") a the DAA [Self Regulatory Program](http://www.aboutads.info/) site. 

The tools provided on the Ad Choices page, as well as the [DAA opt-out page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and the [NAI opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), are provided by third parties, not Racing-reference.info, we do not control or operate these tools or the choices that advertisers and others provide through these tools. 

When using a mobile application you may receive tailored in-application advertisements. Depending on your device, you may be able to reset your mobile device's advertising identifier at any time by accessing the privacy settings on your mobile device. In addition, each operating system, iOS for Apple phones, Android for Android devices and Windows for Microsoft devices, provides its own instructions on how to prevent the delivery of tailored in-application advertisements. You may review support materials and/or the privacy settings for the respective operating systems in order to opt-out of tailored in-application advertisements. For any other devices and/or operating systems, please visit the privacy settings for the applicable device or contact the applicable platform operator. 

**_How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals_**

At this time Racing-reference.info does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include "do not track" instructions. 

**_Sharing Your Information_**

Rest assured that we neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone and that we will share your personal information only as described below. 

Racing-reference.info Personnel: Racing-reference.info personnel and authorized consultants and/or contractors may have access to user information if necessary in the normal course of Racing-reference.info business. 

Business Transfers: In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Racing-reference.info, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred. 

Protection of Racing-reference.info and Others: We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other policies; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Racing-reference.info, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

Syndication: Racing-reference.info allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the Racing-reference.info website. 

With Your Consent: Except as noted above, we will contact you when your personal information is shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to opt out to prevent the sharing of this information. 

**_Children Under 18 Years of Age_**

You must be 13 years and older to register to use the Racing-reference.info website. As a result, Racing-reference.info does not specifically collect information about children. If we learn that Racing-reference.info has collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. We recommend that minors between the ages of 13 and 18 ask and receive their parents' permission before using Racing-reference.info or sending information about themselves or anyone else over the Internet. 

**_Changes to this Privacy Policy_**

Racing-reference.info may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Racing-reference.info website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances if any, it is disclosed. 

**_Conditions of Use_**

If you decide to visit Racing-reference.info website, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of Florida state law. 

**_How to Contact Us/Opting Out of Marketing Communications_**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, or if you would like to opt out from our sharing of your personal Information with unaffiliated third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes you may contact us at the address below and request that we opt you out of such sharing. We may ask you to provide additional information for identity verification purposes, or to verify that you are in possession of an applicable email account. 

Racing-reference.info   
c/o NASCAR Legal Department   
One Daytona Boulevard   
Daytona Beach, FL 32114   
email: [copyrightagent@racing-reference.info](mailto://copyrightagent@racing-reference.info)

If you have signed up to receive our e-mails and prefer not to receive marketing information from this site, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions provided on any marketing e-mail you receive from this site. If you have signed up to receive text messages from us and no longer wish to receive such messages, you may follow the instructions to stop delivery of such messages, which may include by replying "STOP" to the received text message. 

**_California Residents - Your California Privacy Rights_**

California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the business' practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. Alternately, businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose personal information of customers to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing. We have such a policy in place. 

As discussed above in How to Contact Us/Opting Out of Marketing Communications, if you wish to opt-out of our sharing of your personal Information with third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes or to find out more about your opt-out rights, please contact us as described above. 

**_International Transfer_**

Racing-reference.info operates globally so it may be necessary to transfer your information internationally. In particular, your information will likely be transferred to and processed in the United States where many of our central databases operate. The data protection and other laws of other countries, such as the United States, may not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using this site you consent to your information being collected, used and transferred as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

**_Effective Date of this Privacy Policy_**

The Privacy Policy posted on this site was updated March 6, 2018. 

© 2018 NASCAR Digital Media, LLC 

[Click here](http://www.racing-reference.info/privacy_old.htm) to view the former privacy policy (effective 5/8/2014) for racing-reference.info.
